Guide to the Cornell Center for Materials Research records, 1970-2008
Cornell Center for Materials Research records
- Series VI. Facilities
  - Ion Beam Facility, Report Preparation, Technical Operations/ Crystal Growing, 1977-1995 (Box 29, Folder 32)
  - Polymer Characterization Facility, Surface Science Synchronization, 1976-1990, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 33)
  - Ceramics Processing, 1980, 1991, 1995 (Box 29, Folder 34)
  - Stem Lab, Computer Services, National Nanofabrication Facility, 1977-1992, 1995 (Box 29, Folder 35)
  - National Nanofabrication Facility (Box 29, Folder 36)
  - National Resource Center for Sub-Micron Structures, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 37)
  - CHESS- Cornell High Energy Synchronization Source, 1979-1982 (Box 29, Folder 38)
  - Signage (Facilities/Labs), Ion Beam Facility Brochure, Space Inventory (Facilities) (Box 29, Folder 39)
  - Space Inventory/ Facilities Inventory- Part I, 1993-2001 (Box 29, Folder 40)
  - Space Inventory/ Facilities Inventory- Part II, 1989-1999 (Box 29, Folder 41)
  - Facility Info., 1996-2001 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Facility Meeting Info., 1997-2001 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Facility Info.- Miscellaneous (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - EPSC Upgrade Microscopy (Hunt/Miller), 1998-1993 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - MSC Facility Review Committee, 1992 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Facilities Reports, Info., 1991-1992 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Past Site Visits, Administrative Report, Central Facilities Subcommittee, 1970-1988 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Facilities Info., 1999-2002 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Facilities-Descriptions, 1971-1974 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Capital Facilities Files-I, 1991 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Capital Facilities Files-II, 1991 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Bard Hall Renovation Project, 1990 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - System 85 Telephone- Meetings, Corresp., 1985 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - MSC Members List, 1997-1998 (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - MSC Faculty and Staff Directory, 1997 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Cornell Property Utilization and Control Systems, 1986 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Capital Equipment Files, 1990 (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Technical Operations Laboratory, 1980's (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - Mechanical Testing Facility, 1985 (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - Metallography & X-ray Facility, 1985-1988 (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - Electron Microscopy Files, 1987-1991 (Box 30, Folder 21)
  - Materials Preparation Facility, 1991 (Box 30, Folder 22)
  - Facility Info. (Box 30, Folder 23)
  - Facility Advisory Committee Records, 2001 (Box 30, Folder 24)
  - Faculty Brochure Distribution, 1999 (Box 30, Folder 25)
  - Facility Information, Dr. Grochala/Hoffman-Support, Fellowship Projects, 1997-2005 (Box 30, Folder 26)
  - Facilities Brochures, 1998-2000 (Box 30, Folder 27)
  - Facility Managers Meetings, 2005 (Box 30, Folder 28)
  - Physical Sciences Building Construction (Site Photographs), 1962-1964 (Box 30, Folder 29)
  - Physical Sciences Building Construction (Site Photographs), 1962-1964 (Box 30, Folder 30)
  - Bard Hall Construction (Site Photographs), 1961-1963 (Box 30, Folder 31)
  - Bard Hall Construction (Site Photographs), 1961-1964 (Box 30, Folder 32)
  - Physical Sciences Building Project Info., 1960 (Box 30, Folder 33)
- Series VII. History of CCMR
  - Conferences Outside Cornell, 1979-1982 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Solid State Science Program Info., Lead Theory Seminar, 13th Field Emission Symposium, 1966-1971 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Workshop on Synchroton Radiation, Cornell Meeting on Application of Field-Ion, Microscopy to Materials Science, Workshop on Analytical Electron Microscopy, 1977-1978 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Analytical Electron Microscopy Workshop, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Advances in Metal Deformation, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Conference on Internal Friction, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Doe Stirling Engine Meeting, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Physical Electronics Conference (40th), 1980 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - National Microscopy Committee Workshop, NSF Site Visit- UHV STEM, 1984-1991 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - APPA- Rockwell Annual NDE, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Colloquims/Seminars, Newspaper Clippings, 1966-1980 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - MSC Members Cirriculum Vitae (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - History- Postdocs/Assts, Departmental Distribution, 1969-1981 (Box 30, Folder 33)
  - History-Reverse Site Visit, 1996 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - History of the Center (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Physics Department History-Paul Hartman (Revised) CD #433 - Hartman History 1992, 1993 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - History of the Center (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - History of Center Renewal Activities, 1995-1996 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - History of Central Renewal Activities-I, 1998-2000 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - History of Central Renewal Activities-II, 1998-2000 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Research Assistants (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Postdoctoral Assistants, Visiting Professors/Seminar, 1971-1995 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Clark Hall and Rockefellar, 1980-1995 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Campus Affairs, Public Affairs, 1966-1993 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Planning and Research, 1978-1992 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Information Technologies, 1989-1991 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Office of the Provost, 1986-1991 (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Office of the Provost, 1984-1985 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Office of the Provost, 1980-1984 (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Dean of University Faculty, 1965-1989 (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Dean of Arts and Sciences, 1961-1991 (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - R.L. Stroull Records, 1986-1997 (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - Personnel Dir. Staff Administration-I, 1975-1988 (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - Personal Dir. Staff Administration-II, 1975-1988 (Box 31, Folder 21)
  - Personnel Memorandums, Policy, 1977-1990 (Box 31, Folder 22)
  - Personnel Training Program, 1978-1997 (Box 31, Folder 23)
  - Educational Outreach Coordinator Position, 1997 (Box 31, Folder 24)
  - MSC Director, 1974 (Box 31, Folder 25)
  - MSC Associate Director, 1965-1967 (Box 31, Folder 26)
  - MSC Associate Director, 1975-1976 (Box 31, Folder 27)
  - MSC Associate Director, 1960,1997 (Box 31, Folder 28)
  - University Correspondence, Day Hall Policies, 1967-1990 (Box 31, Folder 29)
  - President, 1963-1996 (Box 31, Folder 30)
  - Physical Sciences Building History, Additional Remarks to "Plans for a MSC at Cornell Unversity", 1959,1964 (Box 31, Folder 31)
  - Board of Trustees, 1971-1985 (Box 31, Folder 32)
  - Cornell Classification Review Study (Box 31, Folder 33)
  - Cornell CAT Proposal, Brief History of the Formative First Decade AAJD, 1992,1996 (Box 31, Folder 34)
- Series VIII. General Files
  Includes material on the budget, faculty and staff, fellowships, workshops, etc.
  - MSC Members Info - I (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - MSC Members Info- II (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - MSC Members Info- III (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - MSC- Organization and Procedures, 1968 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - MSC- Organization and Procedures, 1968 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - MSC- Procedures, 1978-1979 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - MSC Review Committee, 1966 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Unit Statement (MSC), 1982-1985 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - MSC- Short Descriptions of Equipment and Capabilities, IAAY Symposium-Info., 1993, 1997 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Biographical Material- MSC GRA's, Postdocs, 1980 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - MSC Members- Ballots and Voting Committee Correspondence, 1983-1986 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - History of MSC Doc 1-11 Vol I, 1956-1960 (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - History of MSC Doc 1-11 Vol II, 1959-1960 (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - MSC History- Statistics, Members (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - MSC History (Hartman Original), MSC Newsletter Vol. 1 No.1, 1990,1992 (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - MSC Support History - By Dept., 1970-1992 (Box 36, Folder 16)
  - History of MSC- Doc 12-28 Vol. II (Part I) (Box 36, Folder 17)
  - History of MSC- Doc 12-28 Vol. II (Part 2) (Box 36, Folder 18)
  - Contribution to MSC Annual Report- I, 1991-1992 (Box 36, Folder 23)
  - Contribution to MSC Annual Report- II, 1991-1992 (Box 36, Folder 24)
  - MSC Staff and Retired Members Info.- J.C. Scott, 1975-1981 (Box 36, Folder 25)
  - MSC Staff and Retired Members Info.- McFarlane, 1969-1979 (Box 36, Folder 26)
  - MSC Staff and Retired Members Info.- R.W. Balluffi, 1964-1969 (Box 36, Folder 27)
  - MSC Staff and Retired Members Info.- KC Dejonghe, 1972-1978 (Box 36, Folder 28)
  - MSC Staff and Retired Members Info.- E.L. Muetterties (Box 36, Folder 29)
  - MSC Staff and Retired Members Info.- R.R. Rye, 1968-1971 (Box 36, Folder 30)
  - MSC Staff and Retired Members Info.- B.W. Maxfield (Box 36, Folder 31)
  - MSC Staff and Retired Members Info.- G.F. Rankin, 1966-1973 (Box 36, Folder 32)
  - MSC Staff and Retired Members Info.- A.J. Bearden, 1960-1965 (Box 36, Folder 33)
  - MSC Staff and Retired Members Info.- G.V. Smith, 1965-1968 (Box 36, Folder 34)
  - MSC Staff and Retired Members Info.- W.S. Owen, 1966-1970 (Box 36, Folder 35)
  - MSC Research Projects, MSC Capital Equipment Requests, 1992 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - MSC Staff and Retired Members Info.- P.S. Ho, 1968-1974 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - MSC Staff and Retired Members Info., 1961-1973 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - MSC Staff and Retired Members Info.- L.H. Germer, 1961-1971 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - MSC Staff and Retired Members Info.- J.L. Gregg, 1960-1967 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - MSC Staff and Retired Members Info.- Dr. A. Taylor, 1960-1977 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - MSC Staff & Retired Members Info. - Bonse, Abowitz & Mixed, 1960's (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - MSC Budget, 1968-1969 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - MSC Budget and Research Proposals, 1969-1970 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - MSC Budget and Research Proposals, 1970-1971 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - MSC Budget, 1968-1969 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - MSC Budget, 1967-1968 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - MSC Review Committee- Dilution Committee, Thin Film Committee, 1976 (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - MSC General Program Areas (Ellipsis), Faculty Survey Record, 1971-1983 (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - MSC Study Groups, Ceramics Program, Surfaces &Interfaces Group, Quantum Phenomena, 1976-1995 (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - MSC Nuggets, 1993-1995 (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - MSC Nuggets for NSF, 1987 (Box 37, Folder 17)
  - MSC Budget, 1979-1980 (Box 37, Folder 18)
  - MSC Budget, 1978-1979 (Box 37, Folder 19)
  - MSC Budget, 1977-1978 (Box 37, Folder 20)
  - MSC Budget, 1980-1981 (Box 37, Folder 21)
  - MSC Budget, 1988-1989 (Box 37, Folder 22)
  - MSC Budget, 1987-1988 (Box 37, Folder 23)
  - MSC Budget, 1986-1987 (Box 37, Folder 24)
  - MSC Budget, 1985-1986 (Box 37, Folder 25)
  - MSC Budget, 1981-1982 (Box 37, Folder 26)
  - MSC Budget, 1991-1992 (Box 37, Folder 27)
  - Responsibility Center Analysis, 1980 (Box 37, Folder 28)
  - MSC, 1989-1990 (Box 37, Folder 29)
  - MSC Mission Statement, Member Files, 1990's (Box 37, Folder 30)
  - MSC Budget, 1990-1991 (Box 37, Folder 31)
  - Annual Call for Nuggets, 1995 (Box 37, Folder 32)
  - Nuggets, 1984 (Box 37, Folder 33)
  - Nuggets, 1982 (Box 37, Folder 34)
  - Nuggets, 1983 (Box 37, Folder 35)
  - Summary of Materials Research Laboratory Nuggets, 1981-1982 (Box 37, Folder 36)
  - NSF Nuggets, June 1981 (Box 37, Folder 37)
  - Nuggets for NSF Annual Report, 1980 (Box 37, Folder 38)
  - MSC Nuggets for Annual Report, 1979 (Box 37, Folder 39)
  - Budget Files- Capital Equipment, 1990.1992 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Research Experience for Minorities- Proposals and Correspondence, 1989,1990 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Weisner Articles, Fellowships, 2000,2001 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - CCMR Fellowships, 1999 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - CCMR Fellowship Applications- I, 1999 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - CCMR Fellowship Applications- II, 1999 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - CCMR Fellowships- Correspondence, 1998 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - CMSC Graduate Research Fellowship Program- General Corresp. & Applications, 1997 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Personnel Change of Status- Silsbee, Johnson, Silcox, 1984,1975,1995 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Infrastructure Proposal Info., 1993 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Patent Agreements, 1994 (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - New Faculty Vitae- Melissa A. Hines (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - MSC Central Facility Statistics, Pre 1990 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Materials Research Community Bulletin, Physics Today, 1995,1996 (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Kramer Nugget- Color Transparency, 1993 (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - CMSC Graduate Research Fellowship Program (Applications), 1997 (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - Freelance- Joe Schwartz, 1999 (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - Sandy Sweazey Farewell Photos, 2001 (Box 38, Folder 18)
  - Smart- NY Presentation, 1999 (Box 38, Folder 19)
  - Master List of PH'Ds, 1964-1976 (Box 38, Folder 20)
  - PHD Records, 1960-1986 (Box 38, Folder 21)
  - PHD's and Industrial Connections, 1987 (Box 38, Folder 22)
  - Original Members List (PHD's), 1960-1986 (Box 38, Folder 23)
  - Publications- First Draft, 1990 (Box 38, Folder 24)
  - GRA's and Postdocs Info., 1985-1991 (Box 38, Folder 25)
  - MSC Postdoc/GRA Info., Helium Users- General Corresp. & Meetings, Supplemental Award Proposal, 1990-2000 (Box 38, Folder 26)
  - List of Reprints and Thesis, 1996-2003 (Box 38, Folder 27)
  - Steady State Levels of Operations- MSC, 1964 (Box 38, Folder 28)
  - Article- Fortune Magazine, 1962 (Box 38, Folder 29)
  - Subcommittee- MSC Directors, 1967-1968 (Box 38, Folder 30)
  - Write-ups- OXR &NSF, Apr 1975 (Box 38, Folder 31)
  - ARPA Review Committee Meeting, Nov 1974 (Box 38, Folder 32)
  - Research Write-Ups (ARPA), 1972-1974 (Box 38, Folder 33)
  - Patent Procedures, 1965-1967 (Box 38, Folder 34)
  - Pending Appointments, 1988-1989 (Box 38, Folder 35)
  - Materials Science Center Proposal, 1960 (Box 38, Folder 36)
  - Survey of Government Agency Support, 1964 (Box 38, Folder 37)
  - Gov't Agency Support- Profiles, Fortune Article on Materials Science, 1964-1965 (Box 38, Folder 38)
  - New Bureau, Life Safety, Radiation Safety, 1971-1989 (Box 38, Folder 39)
  - Controller, Development Offices, 1959-1997 (Box 38, Folder 40)
  - Sponsored Programs- I, 1964-1991 (Box 38, Folder 41)
  - Sponsored Programs- II, 1964-1991 (Box 38, Folder 42)
  - NSF Science and Technology Centers, 1987 (Box 38, Folder 43)
  - International Travel Grant Forms, NSF Reports- Peer Review System, 1975-1980 (Box 38, Folder 44)
  - Assistant to the President, 1971-1996 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - NSF-MRC, Labs & Groups (Including MRSEC), NSF- Research write-ups for contribution to NSF Records, 1973,1978,1995 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Research Highlights of MSC, 1971,1973,1975 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - MRSEC- FY SG Reviews, 1996 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - NSF/MRL Program Evaluations, 1984-1989 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - NSF/MRL Program Evaluations, 1982-1984 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Norfolk State- Proposal, NSF Jackson State Prem/McEven, 2005 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - NSF Parpia/Craighead, 2005 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - NSF-Singhota, General Motors Mathias, Proposals in Progress, NSF Fastlane Info., 1998-2002, 2005 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - NSF-SIA DiSavlo, Pending- Simmons Malliaras, 2004-2005 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Executive Summaries- MRSEC (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Articles on MSC Faculty, 1990's (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Ashcroft Appreciation Dinner, Aug 2000 (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - 'The Bottom Line' Publication, CCMR News Notebook Corresp., 1999-2000 (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - Catetculd Project- Chentura, Balasubramanium, 2000 (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Circulated Materials, 2001 (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - New Computers, 2001 (Box 39, Folder 17)
  - Engineering Cornell Magazines, 1998-2001 (Box 39, Folder 18)
  - Rich Cochran Event, 1998 (Box 39, Folder 19)
  - Condensed Matter and Materials Physics Publication (Proofs), 1999 (Box 39, Folder 20)
  - Connecting with Cornell, 1990's (Box 39, Folder 21)
  - CCMR Duffield, 1998 (Box 39, Folder 22)
  - Directory Listing Info., 2001 (Box 39, Folder 23)
  - Cornell Today, 1999 (Box 39, Folder 24)
  - Annual Report Reference, 1990-1991 (Box 39, Folder 25)
  - Publications- Internal Proposals, 1990-1991 (Box 39, Folder 26)
  - Publications for Internal Proposals, 1993-1994 (Box 39, Folder 27)
  - PHD Study- Msc Supported PHD's (List), 1994 (Box 39, Folder 28)
  - Information Resources, 1984 (Box 39, Folder 29)
  - Word Processing Systems, 1985 (Box 39, Folder 30)
  - Materials Science Center Summaries, 1986 (Box 39, Folder 31)
  - Materials Workshops- Reports, 1990 (Box 39, Folder 32)
  - Laboratory, Program Guides (Misc.) (Box 39, Folder 33)
  - Materials Research Laboratories Program- Research Highlights, 1991-1992 (Box 39, Folder 34)
  - Polymer and Polymer Composites Study Group, 1990 (Box 39, Folder 35)
  - Post DOCS, GRA Budget Status, 1978 (Box 39, Folder 36)
  - Wiesner, Ulrich Shear Orientation, Moax Planck Society Collaboration, Kwangju Institue of Sci. & Tech., 1998,2000 (Box 39, Folder 37)
  - Clark Hall Wiring, CCMR Membership Letters, Final Report DMR-96322575, Cooperative Agreements, 1996-2000, 2004 (Box 39, Folder 38)
  - Princeton Program Research Needs for Future & Princeton Connector Copies from Kramer's Papers, 1984 (Box 39, Folder 39)
  - Chemical Hygiene Plan, 1999 (Box 39, Folder 40)
  - White Paper on 'Costs of Educating MS and PHD Students in the Physical Sciences and ENGG. at Cornell', 1990 (Box 39, Folder 41)
  - Budget Files- Capital Equipment, 1990-1991 (Box 39, Folder 42)
  - Capital Equipment Needs- Budget Files, 1991-1992 (Box 39, Folder 43)
  - DOE Program Review and Program Summary - Frederick Setiz Materials Research Lab, February 2005; 435 (Box 40)
- Series IX. Photographs, Slides, Video
  - MSC Photo Slides, 1993 (Box 36, Folder 19)
  - MSC Photo Slides, 1993-1996 (Box 36, Folder 20)
  - MSC Photo Slides- Research Projects, 1993 (Box 36, Folder 21)
  - MSC Photo Slides-Research Projects, 1991,1993 (Box 36, Folder 22)
  - Don Miller Campus Photos (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Photos of REU and CCMR, 426-432 (Box 40)
  - Cornell Nanofabrication Facility - Video Tour, 2000; V-7045